KANG LIU

tomsheep.cn@gmail.com

+8613552593473

Profile

A full-stack engineer candidate with good sense of Data Mining, Web Development and DevOps.

Skills

Web Stack

Practitioner of Web development, with experience in Front-End/Back-End programming with Python/JavaScript.

Hadoop Stack

Practitioner of Hadoop eco-system, familiar with Spark/Hive/Impala/Hbase.

Data Mining Stack

Practitioner of Statistics and Machine Learning algorithms, skilled at PyData stack (numpy/scipy/pandas/matplotlib).

DevOps

Practitioner of Agile Development, familiar with DevOps tools such as Docker, Jenkins, Git, etc.

Experience

gomegj.com - Beijing

Architect

Responsible for data platform architecting of gomegi.com.

Xiaomi Inc. - Beijing

Technical Manager

Apr 2014-Jun 2016

Jun 2016-Current

Responsible for the development of BI system for TV department, providing multi-dimensional data analysis tools for the business team. The system is built on open source project Mondrian and ETL tools including Hive and Impala.

Responsible for the development of recommender system for the Online Video app on Xiaomi TV, providing personalized movie recommedations for end users. The system is built with Spark, Hbase and ElasticSearch.

Douban Inc. - Beijing

Algorithm Engineer

Jul 2012-Apr 2014

Work on recommender system for Douban Homepage, which is a half Facebook half IMDB website, with collaborative-filtering and text-minging skills.

Yahoo! Inc. - Beijing Software Engineer

Jul 2011-Jul 2012

Responsible for development of the prototype for Yahoo! Messenger, which adopts a hybrid architecture. Native technology(QT/Webkit) is used for the main logic and Web stack(HTML/JS/CSS) for the UI.

Education

Fudan University - Shanghai, China

2007-2011 Software Enigneering — **3.76 GPA(Rank 1/88)**

Graduated with a B.E degree as No.1 in GPA. Got first-class scholarships and Individual Gold Medals for 3 years in a row.